{"tossups": [{"question": "This president\u2019s Secretary of War, George Crawford, resigned after his implication in the Galphin Affair. This president settled a Nicaraguan canal dispute with the British in the Clayton-Bulwer Treaty. Prior to his presidency, this man led a volunteer army against a far larger force led by Santa Anna at the Battle of Buena Vista. This man defeated Winfield Scott as the Whig candidate in the U.S. presidential election of 1848. For the point, name this president who died in office and was known as \u201cOld Rough and Ready.\u201d", "answer": "Zachary<b> Taylor</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "1 billion taels. The Eight Trigrams uprising occurred during this dynasty after the Heavenly Principle Sect broke from another group when a tax was levied against the White Lotus movement by Hongli, the Qianlong Emperor. Zeng Guofan studied the aforementioned rebellion when putting down the later Taiping Rebellion during this dynasty. For the point, name this dynasty that succeeded the Ming.", "answer": "Great<b> Qing</b> Dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "One philosopher with this last name was the author of<em> The History of British India</em>. That philosopher\u2019s daughter-in-law married into this last name and co-authored the proto-feminist work<em> The Subjection of</em> <em>Women</em>. Her husband with this last name was a utilitarian philosopher who argued for women\u2019s suffrage as a member of Parliament. For the point, give this last name shared by a Scottish economist, James, and his daughter-in-law, Harriet Taylor, as well as her husband, a British philosopher who defended free speech in the essay<em> On Liberty</em>.", "answer": "<b> Mill</b> (accept James<b> Mill</b>, Harriet Taylor<b> Mill</b>, and/or John Stuart<b> Mill</b>)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s \u201cThree Represents\u201d were written into his country\u2019s constitution, and he created the 6-10 office to deal with the Falun Gong. The \u201csocialist market economy\u201d was developed by this man after his predecessor\u2019s \u201copening up and reform.\u201d After rumors that this man had died, he was seen at the Great Hall of the People on the 100th anniversary of the Xinhai Revolution. This former Shanghai mayor was succeeded by Hu Jintao in his highest position. For the point, name this paramount leader of China who succeeded Deng Xiaoping as China\u2019s military commander-in-chief.", "answer": "<b> Jiang</b> Zemin Page 1", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In a scheme to surrender this city, Belgian consul \u00b4Edouard Andr\u00b4e suggested that the signal \u201cD.W.H.B.\u201dwas to be used. Prior to that surrender, in a battle for this city\u2019s port, the message that \u201conly 15 rounds per gun had been used\u201d was mistaken as \u201conly 15 rounds per gun remain,\u201d causing a break in the battle for breakfast. That battle for this city ended with Francis Randall\u2019s death by heart attack as the only American fatality. The USS<em> Olympia</em> was commanded by George Dewey in the bay of, for the point, what Philippine city?", "answer": "<b> Manila</b> (accept<b> Manila</b> Bay)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A victim of this ruler\u2019s military campaign buried the Fenwick treasure. A divining hare was released from the folds of the clothing of this ruler, who then laid siege to a temple for Claudius for two days, taking a bronze head of Nero as a trophy. This ruler\u2019s forces were later trapped by a ring of their own wagons. This ruler trounced the Ninth Legion but was defeated by Suetonius at the Battle of Watling Street. The towns of Verulamium, Camulodunum, and Londinium were sacked by, for the point, what Iceni [ai-SEE-nai] warrior queen who led a revolt against Rome in Britain?", "answer": "<b> Boudica</b> (accept<b> Boadicea</b>, accept pronunciations with a hard or a soft \u201cC\u201d)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This body holds 150-day regular sessions, autumn extraordinary sessions, and special sessions which often involve choosing a prime minister-designate. For almost six decades, this body featured a House of Peers that was replaced after World War Two by a House of Councillors. After the 2019 elections, a strong majority in both houses of this body was retained by the LDP and Komeito. This body first convened in its \u201cImperial\u201d form in 1890 under the Meiji Constitution. For the point, name this bicameral legislature of Japan.", "answer": "National<b> Diet</b> of Japan (accept<b> Kokkai</b>) Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This figure wounded rival Matt Stewart in the shoulder during a shoot-out over control of advertising space. This figure\u2019s FBI file includes an invitation to J. Edgar Hoover to \u201cshow those young people what celebratin\u2019s about\u201d at this figure\u2019s corporate-sponsored 80<em>th</em>birthday party in 1970. On the panel show<em> What\u2019s My Line?</em>, this businessman was told he was \u201ctoo beautiful to work\u201d in his white suit, which he began wearing along with a trademark goatee in the 1950s. For the point, name this American entrepreneur who founded Kentucky Fried Chicken.", "answer": "Colonel Harland David<b> Sanders</b> (accept Colonel Harland F.<b> Sanders</b>, as he appears with that initial in FBI documents)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This woman was reported to have recruited women to dress as Amazons. This woman\u2019s support for her uncle Raymond of Poitier\u2019s campaigns against the County of Edessa was a source of contention between this woman and her husband, Louis VII. Pope Eugene III annulled that marriage, after which this woman married the Plantagenet king, Henry II, the father of her sons, Richard the Lionhearted and John. For the point, name this woman, born a duchess from a region of southwestern France, who became queen of both France and England.", "answer": "<b> Eleanor of Aquitaine</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This party expanded women\u2019s rights after winning all but three seats in the Massachusetts legislature in 1854. Levi Boone was a mayor of Chicago from this party who sparked the Lager Beer Riot. During a namesake Baltimore riot that took place during the election of Thomas Swann, this party allied with gangs like the Plug Uglies. Millard Fillmore was reluctant to comment on the activities of this party, even though he was nominated by them in 1856. For the point, name this xenophobic U.S. political party.", "answer": "<b> Know Nothing</b>(s) (accept Native<b> American</b> Party)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In 1977, in this state\u2019s town of Alexander City, the Reverend Willie Maxwell was killed at the funeral for his stepdaughter, his fifth relative to have mysteriously died after Maxwell took out life insurance polices on them. Casey Cep\u2019s 2019 book<em> Furious Hours</em> details how that case nearly inspired the book <em>The Reverend</em>, which was never finished by an author from this state who worked as a research assistant on<em> In Cold Blood</em>. For the point, name this state where a rape near Monroeville inspired Harper Lee\u2019s<em> To</em> <em>Kill a Mockingbird</em>.", "answer": "<b> Alabama</b> Page 3", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "This leader was the only person in the 19th century to die as a member of the House of Representatives and then lie in state in the U.S. Capitol building. This leader went beyond the Ironclad Oath by proposing total disenfranchisement for five years. This leader claimed that certain territories were \u201cconquered provinces,\u201d and thus legal protections did not apply to them. Along with John Bingham, this leader introduced articles of impeachment against Andrew Johnson. For the point, name this leader of the Radical Republicans during Reconstruction.", "answer": "Thaddeus<b> Stevens</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country was the site of an inland customs line that utilized the \u201cGreat Hedge\u201d to collect taxes, stretching to the state of Orissa in the southeast of this country. The Rowlatt Act granted authorities in this country emergency powers which were invoked when Colonel Reginald Dyer\u2019s troops fired on nonviolent protesters at the Golden Temple in Amritsar. One leader of this country led a march to Dandi to protest the British Raj\u2019s tax on salt. For the point, name this country whose independence movement was led by Mohandas Gandhi.", "answer": "<b> India</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In this city in 1805, Napoleon, who was about to be crowned king, ordered the facade finished on a cathedral, and one of the spires was topped with a statue of him. A pair of Italo Calvino-inspired towers containing the Bosco Verticale, were completed in 2014 in this city\u2019s Porta Nuova district. This city\u2019s Porta Ticinese is home to the Roman ruins of the Colonne di San Lorenzo. Santa Maria delle Grazie, which houses Leonardo\u2019s<em> Last Supper</em>, is in, for the point, what city in Lombardy, the location of the La Scala opera house?", "answer": "<b> Milan</b>o", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This leader jumped into the arms of Chuck Connors, the star of his favorite TV show,<em> The Rifleman</em>, one of the few American programs aired in this man\u2019s country. This leader consolidated power after the failure of the Kosygin reforms. A doctrine named for this man was used to justify ousting the leader of the KSC and assassinating the leader of the PDPA. This leader signed both SALT treaties, but that did not stop him from authorizing an invasion of Afghanistan. For the point, name this Soviet leader who succeeded Nikita Khrushchev.", "answer": "Leonid<b> Brezhnev</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In one of these structures, the central object was surrounded by 20,000 marine-shell disc beads in the shape of a falcon. The Ho-Chunk people are the primary visitors to the \u201ceffigy\u201d types of these structures, which are built in the shape of stylized animals. Henry Brackenridge named the largest \u201cplatform\u201d type of these structures called \u201cMonks\u201d in Collinsville, Illinois. \u201cBuilders\u201d of these structures constructed over 100 at Cahokia and a \u201cGreat Serpent\u201d one in Ohio. For the point, name these piles of earth often used by Native Americans for burial purposes.", "answer": "Burial<b> mound</b>s (accept Cahokia<b> Mound</b>s before \u201cHo-Chunk\u201d)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {"question": "As an apprentice, this man sailed with John Lok, an ancestor of philosopher John Locke, to West Africa. Sailing with the<em> Gabriel</em> and the<em> Michael</em> for Queen Elizabeth I, this explorer sailed to what he believed was Labrador. While on a search for the Northwest Passage, this man thought he discovered gold, but the 1350 tons of rock he brought home turned out to be hornblende. A US Air Force base in Nunavut bore this man\u2019s name. For the point, name this English explorer who names a bay on the southeast corner of Baffin Island.", "answer": "Martin<b> Frobisher</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "Stephen Puter hired saloon patrons in this state to help fraudulently claim land, which led to the indictments of this state\u2019s congressmen, John H. Mitchell and John Williamson. The only active senator to die in battle was this state\u2019s Edward Dickinson Baker at Ball\u2019s Bluff. Alaska\u2019s Ernst Gruening and a senator from this state, Wayne Morse, opposed the Gulf of Tonkin Resolution. Jeff Merkley and Ron Wyden are senators from, for the point, what Pacific Northwest state that, in 2016, became the first to elect an openly LGBT governor, Kate Brown?", "answer": "<b> Oregon</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This group\u2019s commander declared that they would \u201crebuild an anti-Germany front,\u201d and they won the Battle of Bakhmach. Maurice Janin, a leader of this group, sold out ally Aleksandr Kolchak for safe passage while also taking control of a train filled with Imperial Gold reserves. This group overran Austrian trenches at the Battle of Zborov in the Kerensky Offensive and were supported by Tom\u00b4as Masaryk. For the point, name this unit that sought Allied support in their battle for independence from Austria-Hungary by fighting Bolsheviks along the Trans-Siberian Railway.", "answer": "<b> Czechoslovak Legion</b> Page 6", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This person was the primary beneficiary in the Hall Carbine Affair. This person formed the Northern Securities Company after allying with James J. Hill to shut out E.H. Harriman from the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad. This person was the junior partner of Anthony Drexel in the formation of a company that ended up financing U.S. Steel. This leader pledged much of his fortune to save U.S. credit during the Panic of 1907. For the point, name this Gilded Age financier whose namesake bank merged with Chase.", "answer": "J(ohn) P(ierpont)<b> Morgan</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this British island in the South Atlantic, the site of Napoleon\u2019s final exile.", "answer": "<b> Saint Helena</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "One speech by this man provoked satire and reference to \u201cblight\u201d-ed communities. Peggy Noonan and Craig Smith wrote a speech for this man that compared volunteering organizations to \u201ca brilliant diversity spread like stars.\u201d Lee Atwater aided this man in attacking an opponent with the \u201cRevolving Door\u201d ad during the 1988 Presidential Election, in which this man read the \u201cThousand Points of Light\u201dspeech. For the point, name this 41st U.S. president who said, \u201cRead my lips: No new taxes.\u201d", "answer": "George<b> H</b>erbert Walker<b> Bush</b> (accept<b> Bush 41</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "After this king\u2019s troops lost at the siege of Amiens, he signed the Treaty of Vervins [vair-VAH] with Henry IV. Though this man\u2019s forces lost at Djerba, his brother beat Uluj Ali with the support of the Holy League of 1571. During this man\u2019s reign, the Duke of Alba held the Council of Blood, and the Seventeen Provinces revolted against him in the Eighty Years\u2019 War. This man ordered the Duke of Medina Sidonia to lead an invasion that lost at Gravelines [grav-LEEN]. For the point, name this son of Charles V who ordered the failed Spanish Armada.", "answer": "<b> Philip II</b> of Spain Page 7", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A plaque at the top of this mountain includes the line \u201cO beautiful for spacious skies.\u201d This mountain\u2019s name is the title of the poem written by Katherine Lee Bates that became the song\u201cAmerica the Beautiful.\u201d The discovery of gold southwest of this mountain around Cripple Creek attracted gold miners called \u201cFifty Niners.\u201d Originally named James Peak, this mountain was renamed in 1890 to honor a general and explorer who climbed this mountain while assessing the southwestern Louisiana Territory. For the point, name this mountain in Colorado.", "answer": "<b> Pikes</b> Peak Page 8", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}], "bonuses": []}